## Siddaharth Suman

Software Engineer III

#### **Objectives**

Looking for a continuous learning environment and professional growth in an organization where my skills are adequately utilized.

I wish to contribute the skills that I have learned over the years for the betterment of the organization.

#### About Me

Software Engineer III with a total experience of 5 years and 9 months and currently working with FactSet Systems India Pvt Ltd.

Self-motivated and adaptable kind of individual who yearns to get his hands on the latest trends in technology. Quick learner and a team player who is neither afraid to take lead nor afraid to ask for help in case I get stuck anywhere. Possess good communication, interpersonal, and leadership skills and can effectively deal with teammates and clients.

## **Experience**

Dec 2018 -Present Software Engineer III

FactSet Systems India Pvt. Ltd.

· Worked on endpoint development, data integration and creation of ui tools for the company

Dec 2015 - Dec 2018 Senior System Engineer

Infosys Ltd.

• Worked on creation of mobile and web applications as well as automating tasks.

Aug 2015 - Oct 2015

Assistant Professor

Institute of Forensic Science

· Taught the subject of Cyber Forensics and Offenses, Php and JavaScript

May 2014 - Oct 2014 Freelancer

Palmate Solutions

Worked as a Backend Web Developer

Jan 2014 - Mar 2014 Intern

TechMeet

Worked as an Android Application Developer

Jun 2013 - Oct 2013

Intern

Opine Solutions

• Worked as an Android Application Developer

#### **Projects**

Endpoint development

Technologies: JavaScript, NodeJS | Team Size: 3

- Endpoint creation for ease of use by clients to request company's dataset and query them
- Worked on three such endpoints and received appreciation and 2 awards

Data Importer

Technologies: Oracle SQL | Team Size: 2

· Package used to import data provided by suppliers to integrate into the company's dataset

Financial data tool

Technologies: Java, Php, WixToolset, Msi | Team Size: 5

- Worked as acting lead on the project and ensured timely delivery of tasks and resolution of issues
- · Received award for the project

lechnol

Assessment Portal

Partner

Technologies: Angular, Bulma, Typescript | Team Size: 8

 Portal for partners of the firm to be assessed on their performance and get recommendation for salary changes

Profile and Rewards Application Technologies: Angular, Bootstrap, jQuery, Typescript | Team Size: 12

- Employee centric dashboard with various reports and details of the employee
- Employees can generate their compensation, health and time off related reports

Workspace Reservation Technologies: Android, Ionic, Cordova | Team Size: 10

- Application for employees for reserving workspaces in their office
- Employees can automatically get reservation when in proximity of workplace

Downloads Report Tool Technologies: Selenium, JavaFX, Apache POI, Microsoft Excel, PhantomJS | Team Size: 1

- $\bullet\,$  Automation tool that generates reports for 80+ production applications
- Reduced the time effort from 1 hour to under 5 minutes

Application Details Portal Technologies: Angular, Php, Servlets, Google Drive, Soap | Team Size: 1

- · Portal for internal details of applications supported by the support team
- · Includes ability for automatic healthcheck for all the applications

**Buy/Sell App** 

**Technologies:** Android, Php, MySQL | **Team Size:** 5

App for a buy/sell platform for company employees

#### Personal Info

#### Phone

+91 9920760964

#### E-mail

siddaharthsuman@gmail.com

#### Date of birth

December 18, 1993

#### Marital Status

Unmarried

#### Github

github.com/SiddaharthSuman

## Frameworks

- JavaScript
- React
- Angular

## Backend Technologies/ Frameworks

• Php

## Mobile Technologies

Android

### **Programming Languages**

Java

# Testing Frameworks and Tools

Selenium

### **Version Control**

• Git

SVN

#### **IDEs and Editors**

Eclipse

 Visual Studio Code

### **Operating Systems**

WindowsLinux

Languages

Mac OS

#### Lilia

English

Hindi

Marathi

## **Education**

## Sep 2011 - May 2015

## Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai University, BE in Computer Engineering, 2015

- Conducted Training and Placement Session on "C++" for final year students
- Held the posts of Assistant Technical Head and Technical Head for Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Java Primer", "Backend Web Development" and "Android Application Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Organised Google Dev Fest for Google Developer's Group

till Mar 2011

Kendriya Vidyalaya INS Hamla, Mumbai

## **Publications**

Feb 2015

Supercharging web applications with Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-1 Feb 2015)

Jun 2015

Information system using Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-3 June 2015)